山巅之城
第二季 第８集
翻译　小碗
字　　幕　　侠
关注新浪微博
@FIX字幕侠
翻译　奶瓶且可爱99
ZIMUXIA.CN
校对　一桶派　时间轴　iiichiii
西沃恩因遭安东·坎贝尔枪击而腹中孩子夭折 她和德库西为此悲痛万分
原 创 翻 译
中英双语字幕
后期　Jason肖　特效　小布
监制　一桶派
ZIMUXIA.CN
原 创 翻 译
中英双语字幕
忘了我替格蕾丝·坎贝尔说过的好话
Forget every nice thing I said about Grace Campbell.
你把她一家人他妈的往死里整
You bury that whole fucking family.
我要寻求公平正义
I want justice.
我要给德库西·沃德讨回公平正义
I want justice for Decourcy Ward.
我要给他老婆讨回公平正义
I want justice for his wife.
格蕾丝·坎贝尔带警察找到他大儿子安东后 安东被波士顿警察托尼·苏福林枪击而亡
我妈还在外边吗
Is my ma still out there?
她跟我们一伙的 安东
She's with us, Anton!
不然你以为我们怎么找到你的
How else would we know where to find you?
不 不
No! No!
-我操  -他妈的怎么回事
- Fuck! - What the fuck happened?
他突然就朝我转过来了 克里斯
He fucking wheeled on me, Chris.
很突然
He wheeled on me!
吉可·莱恩发现了她母亲卡茜的贩毒行径 这让她们一家都笼罩在危险中
别他妈碰我
Don't fucking touch me!
杰基·罗尔因涉及霍莉·冈纳过量吸毒一事而被调查
别 霍莉
No. Holly!
珍妮得知曾在她小时候性侵过她的父亲 现在还活着
去你妈的
You know what? Fuck you.
老娘自己去找
Yeah. I'm gonna find him myself.
等你找到他可别想着能大团圆
And if you do, don't expect a touching reunion.
为了帮助梅芙逃脱她爱尔兰共和军的过去 珍妮以朋友的身份借给了梅芙一笔钱
我做出了选择
Now, I made this choice.
它会一直提醒着我 告诉我是谁 代表着谁
It's a permanent reminder of who I am, what I stand for.
拿去吧
Go on.
我是做的好事 并且我还感觉很不错
I did a good deed, and I feel good about that!
所以请你把嘴闭上让我享受下
So shut up and let me have this.
罗尔
Rohr.
还以为你已经去莱克维尔分局了呢
Thought you were off to Lakeville.
你又去跪舔了谁啊
Who'd you have to screw to stay?
还没来得及舔呢
No one... yet.
说说这又出了什么幺蛾子
Now tell me what the fuck's going on,
不然我就开始散布
or I'm gonna start a little rumor
你跟你搭档在你车里边
that you and your partner are playing dick hockey
玩击剑的事情了
in the back of your Toyota.
昨晚一起军火交易没谈拢...
Arms deal went belly up last night...
死了三个爱尔兰人和一个希腊人
Three bog-trotters and a Greek.
这些棺材是拿来装武器的
Used the casket to smuggle weapons.
一共有五把步枪 两把半自动步枪 还有好几把手枪
Got five rifles, two semi-automatics, couple of handguns.
他们打算把这些东西
To what exotic location
运到那个鬼地方去啊
were they attempting to transport the weapons?
爱尔兰
Ireland.
我猜是运给爱尔兰共和军的
To the IRA, I'm guessing.
"杀人是该被禁止的 除非"
"Killing is forbidden unless you kill in large numbers
[出自伏尔泰 法国思想家]
"是在军号声中的屠戮"
and to the sound of trumpets."
你认识这个人吗
You know this one?
从来没见过
Never seen her before in my life.
德库西 见到你真好
Decourcy. Good to see you.
我很高兴你缓过来了
I'm glad you came out to play.
你就打算跟我玩这套吗
That's what we're doing? Playing?
我哪知道 我还没醉呢
I'm not sure. I'm still sober.
双份威勒波本酒 倒两杯里
Weller, double, but in two glasses.
-好的  -轩尼诗加冰
- Very good. - Hennessy, rocks, please.
你敢相信那个罗德尼·金在洛杉矶惹出的乱子吗
You believe this clusterfuck in Los Angeles... Rodney King?
[非裔美国人 因超速而遭警方追捕 截停后拒捕袭警 被四名白人警察暴力制服 该事件引发了日后的洛杉矶暴动]
两个警察被判有罪
Two cops were found guilty.
另两个和本丢·彼拉多[钉死耶稣的犹太总督一样有罪的
Yeah, and two more, guilty as Pontius Pilate,
不也逍遥法外了
were deemed innocent.
您的酒
Here you go.
-谢谢  -不用谢
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
你叫我来这肯定不是为了
All right, now, look, you didn't call me here to talk
谈洛杉矶出的乱子的
about shitstorms in Los Angeles?
我希望你和我一起作为公诉方参加凯尔文的庭审
I want you at the table with me for Kelvin Campbell's trial.
不
No.
布拉克斯顿顶峰社区就像是个马蜂窝
What we have in Braxton Summit is a hornet's nest
那些居民用毒品和凶案
stinging this city a thousand times a day
残害着这个城市
with drugs and killings.
凯尔文他哥枪击了我妻子
Kelvin's brother shot my wife.
我去参加庭审
Sitting at his trial would look like
显得像是小学生寻仇
I'm after schoolyard revenge.
对你们来说是复仇 但对大众就是为了正义
Revenge to some, justice to most.
你也不需要我
You don't need me.
这案子很明白的
The case is all there.
用重罪谋杀规则就行
Just use the-the rule of felony murder.
[重罪犯实施犯罪过程中造成他人死亡 即使该犯不是凶手或无意杀人 也可以被指控谋杀]
科普兰帮的人被布拉克斯顿男孩的人干掉了
A Copeland gang member was killed by a Braxton boy.
不论是不是凯尔文·坎贝尔下的手
Doesn't matter if Kelvin Campbell
能证明他当时在场就足够了
pulled the trigger... He was present.
罪名成立 就那么简单
End of story. Guilty as charged.
我的天
Jesus.
你还真是自以为是地笃信法条啊
You are so goddamn full of self-righteous piety,
你没懂我的意思
you don't see what I'm asking.
陪审团里有五个白人 七个黑人
The jury is five whites, seven Blacks.
不管凯尔文有多罪孽深重
Doesn't matter how guilty Kelvin is.
我站在法庭上控诉他
I'll look like a towering, vindictive Caucasian bully
都只像是凶恶白人在欺负黑人小孩
trying to convict a baby-faced kid.
所以你要我去给你加点黑人辅助
You need me to be your token Black boy.
我只希望你尽职
I want you to do your fucking job.
我这么说是出于礼貌
I'm asking to be polite.
那个苏福林
Suferin.
青年暴力打击部队的警官 托尼·苏福林...
The Youth Strike Task Force Officer Tony Suferin...
你要把他拿下
I want his fucking badge,
让他因为谋杀安东·坎贝尔去坐牢
I want him in Walpole for executing Anton Campbell,
还必须由你全权负责
and I want all your attention paid to the cause.
等把凯尔文定罪了都好说
After we convict Kelvin, yes.
女歌星 在写什么呢
Annie Lennox, what are you writing?
别碰
Don't touch that!
还因为我没去听你礼拜日的独唱生气呢
You still pissed off about me missing that church solo?
你那个朋友梅芙去了吗
Was your little friend Maeve there?
没
No.
但我也没期待她会来
But I didn't expect her to.
现在梅芙说不定
Right now Maeve's probably sitting on a beach
躺在加州哪个海滩上喝鸡尾酒呢
somewhere in California, sipping a mai tai.
她能去别处开始新人生 我为她高兴
I'm happy for her, starting a new life somewhere,
我也很高兴这是因为我帮了她
and I'm happy I helped her get there.
我们有时候会做自认为正确的事
Yeah, well, sometimes we do things that we think are good,
但结果却不如人意
but they don't necessarily turn out that way, you know?
你这话说的 感觉下一句
That sounds like something you tell somebody
就要告诉别人噩耗了
before you give them bad news.
不 没有的事
No, no, no, no. No.
你为梅芙做的... 是好事
You-you... what you did was good... for Maeve.
你那个教堂独唱
And-and, listen, you know, about the church solo,
-我下次一定会去的 我发誓  -你说是就是吧
I'm gonna be there next time, - I swear to God. - Yeah.
我觉得上帝也听够了
I'm guessing God's pretty tired
你对他老人家发的誓了
of hearing you swear to Him all the time.
-过来 快  -天哪 你干嘛呢
- Come here. Come here. - God, what are you doing?
这就是你道歉的方式吗
Is this your way of saying "I'm sorry"?
没错
Yep.
行吧 我接受了
Okay. Okay.
女士 再给我点糖吧
Miss, I'm gonna need some more sugar.
不担心得糖尿病吗
You're not worried about diabetes?
我这是在让我的心脏不要注意到接下来的心绞痛
I'm distracting my heart from the impending angina.
但我猜你来这
But... I'm guessing that you're not here
不是来和我谈保持健康这个话题的
out of concern for my continued good health.
我有活找你干
I have a project for you.
我知道你因为霍莉·冈纳的事现在如履薄冰
I know there's thin ice under your feet 'cause of Holly Gunner.
这活做了可能就帮你消灾免难了
This could help you skate across that ice.
我跟霍莉·冈纳的事没关系
Holly Gunner's got nothing to do with me,
不过你想找我帮忙 我还是乐意听下的
but if you're interested in my assistance, I'm happy to listen.
那个枪击了坎贝尔的警察... 托尼·苏福林
Cop who shot Campbell... Tony Suferin.
我想把他送进大牢
I want to put him away.
安东·坎贝尔是被他谋杀的
He murdered Anton Campbell.
这不就能让你引人注目 王者归来的回归大案吗
That could be the big, splashy front-page comeback?
总比调职到那个鸟不拉屎的地方好吧
I mean, it'll keep you from getting transferred to nowhere.
你找我
Me?
你想让我帮你把一个白人警察拉下马
You want me to help you bust a white cop?
不用了 谢谢
No, thanks.
西沃恩
Siobhan.
我们能谈谈吗
I was hoping we could talk.
可以 来我办公室谈吧
All right, come up to the office.
这是私事 不是谈案子
It's personal, not a legal matter.
-你是来谈凯尔文的事吗  -对
- You here about Kelvin? - Yes.
那不就两者都占了吗
Seems to me that's personal and legal.
西沃恩 我真觉得凯尔文还有希望
Siobhan, I truly believe that there's still hope for Kelvin.
我希望他还能有机会
I want him to have a chance
去上学 找工作 组建家庭
to finish school, find a job, have a family.
我一直都很崇拜你... 可能甚于我母亲
I've always admired you... maybe more than my own mother.
你对社区的影响
Your impact on the community
是我选择就读法学院的原因...
is what inspired me to go to law school...
而我在那里了解了犯罪的定义
where I studied the definition of crime,
事实与证据的真实面目
the reality of evidence and facts.
可能凯尔文本性不坏 但不管怎么说...
Maybe deep down Kelvin is a good kid, but the bottom line...
他触犯了法律
He broke the law.
我明白了
I see.
你就是因为安东的事想报复
This is nothing more than payback for Anton.
你少这么说了 格蕾丝
Don't you go there, Grace.
是安东把雷娜从她父母身边夺走的
Anton took Raina from Gloria and Darron.
他枪击我 也夺走了我的未来
When he shot me, he took away my future.
我衷心的为你的痛苦哀伤
I grieve for your pain. I do.
我也向上帝祈祷能保佑你
And I pray that God fills your heart once more.
但是我们的孩子都是被这个制度害死的
But the system killed both our babies.
安东是成年人了 他清楚自己行为的后果
Anton is a grown man who knew what he was doing.
西沃恩 我可是看着我儿子死去的
Siobhan, I watched my son die.
我的孩子死在我腹中
Mine died inside of me!
是
Yes.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
真的吗
You are?
那你怎么不一开始就给我道歉
Then why wasn't that the first thing you said?
莱恩太太
Mrs. Ryan?
你来这干嘛
What are you doing here?
我读了戴尔·卡耐基[人际关系教育奠基人的一本书
I read a book by a guy, um, Dale Carnegie,
他说一个成功的商人
and he says a good businessman
要和他的分销商搞好关系
should get close to his subcontractors.
我孩子就在后边
Look, my kids are two seconds behind me.
能不能等周四了
Can we please just meet at the Ebb Tide
再到说好的落潮酒吧碰面
on Thursday like we agreed?
上次会面你就错过了
You missed our last appointment.
你欠我的该还了
You need to pay me what you owe.
可以再宽限几天吗
I need a couple more days.
孩子挺可爱
Cute kids.
快点 走了
Guys. Come on.
公交来了 快上车
Bus is here. Let's go.
那就落潮酒吧见了
I'll see you at the Ebb Tide.
莱恩太太
And, Mrs. Ryan?
这次别迟到了
Don't be late.
妈 那是谁啊
Ma, who was that?
你别管 快上车
Don't worry about it. Just let's go.
快点
Come on. Come on.
手上的绷带呢
Where's your sling?
我今天去见医生了 他说我没事了
Well, I went to the doctor today, and he said I was fine.
接着做康复训练就行
I just need to keep doing the exercises.
可太好了
That's wonderful.
格蕾丝今天到我公司来见我了
And then Grace paid me a lovely visit at the office.
是因为凯尔文审判的事吗
About Kelvin's trial?
还有想替安东给我道歉
That, and she attempted to apologize for Anton,
但我没准
but I didn't let her.
她想求你原谅
Just 'cause she asked for forgiveness
但你不是一定要原谅她
doesn't mean you have to be ready for that.
-是  -可以一直不原谅的
- Yeah. - You don't ever have to be.
不必纠结
Not ever.
所以我就撒了谎 说我不打算帮凯尔文
So, instead, I lied and said I wouldn't help Kelvin,
可实际上 我想帮也帮不了
when the truth is, I can't do a damn thing about it.
他还那么年轻
He's so young.
住在像罗克斯伯里那样的社区...
In Roxbury, in those projects.
西沃恩 听我说...
No, Siobhan, look...
布拉克斯顿顶峰社区的大部分年轻人
the majority of young people in Braxton Summit
都没有做像那兄弟俩那样的选择
haven't made the choices that he and his brother made.
那是因为格蕾丝拼尽全力给了他们更好的选择
Yeah, and Grace worked really hard to give them better options.
让凯尔文逍遥法外
Letting Kelvin walk away from what he's done
不是正确的选择
is not the right answer.
我不是说他是无辜的
I'm not saying that he's innocent.
但我觉得... 他不该因为他控制不了的过去
I'm just saying that, you know, he... he shouldn't be crushed
而被彻底打倒
for a past that he didn't deserve.
换个话题吧
I don't know. Let's just change the subject.
工作如何
How was work?
我跟进了好几个月的诉讼
Well, the lawsuit I've been working on for months
被转给迈尔斯负责了
was handed over to Myers.
合伙人们都把我当个宝贝一样供着
Partners are coddling me like I'm a porcelain doll, fragile.
他们只想给你最好的
They just want what's best for you.
是啊
Yeah.
但我自己才知道什么是对我最好的
Yeah, well, I'm the only person who knows what's best for me,
我如果觉得我准备好工作了 那就一定准备好了
and if I say I'm ready to work, I'm ready to work.
你没收到我的消息吗
Did you get my messages?
过去一个小时我都在联系你
I've been trying to reach you for an hour.
我刚刚在开会 这事重要吗
I got a meeting. Is this important?
对我来说没啥大不了 但和你关系就大了
For me, no. For you, very.
专业职责办公室的人
The Office of Professional Responsibility
叫你去会谈
is calling you in for a review.
他们可不会无缘无故地
The board doesn't conduct these interviews
找人谈话
unless they're sure they have cause.
调职到莱克维尔的事也别想了
So you can forget about a transfer to Lakeville.
这下你说不定工作都得丢
This could mean a boot to your backside.
你知道普罗维登斯的市长巴迪·钱奇吗
Do you know Buddy Cianci? Mayor of Providence?
因为打了睡他前妻的人
Convicted of assaulting the guy
被判了刑
who was sleeping with his ex-wife.
他是我的榜样
He's my hero.
白手起家 职业生涯辉煌
Comes from nothing, amazing career.
即便在被迫辞职之后
Even after they forced him to resign,
也能东山再起 重新当选市长
he still came back and got reelected as mayor.
没有什么能阻挡他
Nothing's stopping the guy.
专业职责办公室会审查你办的每件案子
They're gonna pick through every case you've ever had,
你做的恶事可不止暴打他人
and you've done a lot worse things than beat up some idiot.
你还记得我参加的那场
You know the raid that I was on?
弄死了安东·坎贝尔的突袭不
The raid that killed Anton Campbell?
我能把那个动黑手的白人警察揪出来
I can deliver the white cop that murdered that kid.
波士顿警方说枪击是正当的
According to the BPD, that shooting was justifiable.
安东脑袋里的子弹
The bullet in the back of Anton's head
可不这么认为 它可不会撒谎
tells a different story, and bullets don't lie.
你想和总统夫妇在白宫
You want to be having dinner at the White House
共进晚宴吗
with Bill and Hillary?
用正义的公民权诉讼
You can bury this rogue, racist cop
起诉那个不服管教的种族主义警察就可以了
with an airtight civil rights case.
你是真的很招人烦
You are such a fucking toothache.
我才不在乎什么白宫晚宴
I don't give a shit about dinner at the White House.
但你在乎当权者去伤害
But you do care about people in authority
普通民众
hurting people that aren't.
-如果你能办到...  -别让专业职责办公室的人找我麻烦
- In return for the white cop... - Make this OPR bullshit go away.
前提是你说的都是真的
Only if what you purport to be true is actually true.
必须要有可信的证人作证
I want a reliable witness willing to testify.
我发誓 没问题
Hand on the Bible. Done.
包我身上了
Done.
华莱士警官
Officer Wallace.
你像是要吃掉金丝雀的老猫 不过呢...
You look like the cat that swallowed the canary, but...
我可不是那金丝雀 罗尔探员
I'm not Tweety Bird, Agent Rohr.
去你妈的
Fuck you.
苏福林开枪之前 你是和他在一块的
You were with Suferin right before he fired that shot,
所以你很清楚他当时是自卫
so you know whether he was defending himself
还是故意杀了安东·坎贝尔
or he executed Anton Campbell.
我什么都没看见
I didn't see shit.
华莱士警官
Officer Wallace.
我查了下你 背景很干净
I looked you up. Your jacket's pretty clean.
波士顿学院犯罪学专业 申请成为州警
BC criminal justice, applied to the Staties,
最后加入波士顿警局
decided to go with the BPD.
有个叫卡罗尔的妻子 孩子快生了
Wife, Carol, kid on the way.
别带我家人
Leave my family out of this.
我知道那个死小鬼不是你杀的
I know you didn't murder that fucking kid.
但我需要你亲口说是苏福林干的
I need to hear you say that he did.
他没干
He didn't.
别那么混蛋
Don't be a dope.
在被询问之前你是要宣誓的
You are gonna be asked under oath about what happened.
你敢撒谎 在乎名声的波士顿警方
If you lie, you're gonna be shit-canned
肯定不会给你好果子吃的
by the estimable Boston police force.
有前途的生涯就那么烟消云散了
A promising career, squashed like a fucking cockroach.
我要是出卖了我同事 我职业生涯也毁了
I rat on a fellow cop, my career's in the toilet.
是 但至少你不用因为做假证蹲二十年大牢了
Yeah, but you're not gonna be doing 20 years for perjury.
新车也不会被收缴
Plus, you get to keep that nifty new car.
我给你点时间
Okay, I'm-I'm gonna give you some time
考虑下两种情况下你的下场吧
to ponder your two alternate realities.
滴
Beep.
时间到
Time's up.
不在这谈
Not here.
行
Okay.
上车吧
I'll drive.
快点
Come on.
阿洛伊修斯·法里西大法官入席 全体起立
All rise for the honorable Judge Aloysius Farisi.
行了 快点开始吧
All right, let's... Let's get this cha-cha started.
高院庭审现在开始
Superior Court is now in session.
案件编号93-CR-3-11-10 马萨诸塞州联邦
Case number 93-CR-3-11-10, Commonwealth of Massachusetts
诉凯尔文·德米特里厄斯·坎贝尔
versus Kelvin Demetrius Campbell.
我爱你
I love you.
地检官盖·丹 请陈述
District Attorney Guy Dan, the floor is all yours.
女士们先生们 这是一件关乎暴力的案件
Ladies and gentlemen... this is a case about violence...
关乎野蛮的暴力
savage violence.
法官大人 我很遗憾地提出反对
Your Honor, I am, regrettably, forced to object.
"野蛮"这个词太具有偏见和冒犯性了
The word "savage" is biased and offensive.
反对无效
Overruled.
凯尔文一次又一次地
Kelvin Campbell has time and time again
证明了他是一个危险的
shown himself to be a dangerous,
-铁石心肠的恶人  -反对
- hard-hearted menace. - Objection!
法官大人 辩方三番五次的打断
Your Honor, this repeated interrupting
显然是他们为了干扰我做开庭陈述
is clearly a tactic by the defense
而使用的计策
to derail my opening statement.
反对无效
Objection overruled.
待会会有你发言的时候 卡利尔先生
You will have your chance to speak, Mr. Kalil.
先让他说完
Let the man finish.
能稍快点吗 盖
Could you dance a little faster, Guy?
控方将证明被告
The State will prove that the defendant
是个毒贩 黑帮成员
is a drug dealer, a gang member,
还与三起谋杀案有关
and a participant in a triple homicide.
你们会从他母亲口中听到... "我儿子是个圣人"
You're going to hear from his mother... "My son is a saint."
而我们会证明他身上所谓的光环都是谎言
Well, we're going to show you that his halo is fake.
辩方会称凯尔文·坎贝尔是无辜的
The defense will say Kelvin Campbell is innocent
因为不是他下的手
because he didn't pull the trigger.
但填装子弹的人能算是无辜吗
But is the man who loads the gun innocent?
鼓励凶手开枪杀人的人
Is the man who cheers the killer on... "Shoot! Shoot!"...
就该脱罪吗
Free of guilt?
庭审期间 我们会检验凯尔文·坎贝尔
During this trial, we will examine the attitudes,
过往的一些态度 行为
the actions of Kelvin Campbell, a man...
以证明他是一个满脑子阴暗想法...
whose life is teeming with dark thoughts...
以及野蛮暴力的人
and, yes, savage violence.
圣诞节礼物提早了嘛
Christmas came early.
我会和萨福克郡地检署进行核对的
I'll compare notes with the Suffolk County DA.
我不都发过誓了
But it's what I promised you, right?
托尼·苏福林对安东·坎贝尔下了毒手
Tony Suferin whacked Anton Campbell.
白人警察 黑人受害者 绝配
White cop, Black victim, bingo.
你那么高兴 让我吃惊啊
Amazing you're so full of joy.
鲁斯·华莱士多半要遭暗算了
Russ Wallace will most likely end up shot in the back.
还是会是同行干的
Friendly fire.
关我屁事 你答应的事办到了吗
Who gives a shit? But did you do your part?
把专业职责办公室那伙人摆平了吗
Did you clear me out of that OPR hearing?
我试过了
I tried.
试过了
You tried?
也不是说你一定会出事了
That doesn't mean it won't go your way.
到时候你只要不那么做自己就行了
All you have to do is not be Jackie Rohr.
你明白你儿子被指控的罪名吗
You understand the charges for which your son is being tried?
我明白 还明白地检官是错误的
I do, and the DA is wrong.
反对
Objection.
法官大人 这个证人又不算法律专家
Your Honor, the witness isn't a legal expert.
但在她儿子上 她是专家 反对无效
She is an expert on her son. Overruled.
为什么地检官错了
Why is the district attorney wrong?
凯尔文的一生都乐于助人
His whole life, Kelvin has been a blessing.
他已经成长为了有着优秀品德的年轻人
He's grown into a young man of strong moral character.
他宁愿代他人受苦
He would rather take on the suffering of others
也不愿看他人遭罪
than see them in pain.
能说得更具体点吗
Can you be more specific?
有个冬天 他把他身上的冬衣
He gave away his winter coat to a neighbor boy
给了邻居一个冻到没法去上学的男孩
who wouldn't walk to school 'cause he was too cold.
同一个冬天 没了冬衣的他
That same winter, without his coat,
目睹了一个老妇人滑倒在冰面摔破了头
he saw an older woman slip on the ice, hit her head.
尽管寒冷刺骨 他还是把那个老妇人搀扶到长椅上 为她祈祷
As cold as he was, he helped her to a bench and prayed with her
在救护车来之前一直陪着她
until the ambulance arrived.
他就是这么个富有同情心的年轻人
That's the kind of compassionate young man he is.
的确
Indeed.
该你询问证人了 盖
Your witness, Guy.
你儿子也是出于同情心才贩毒的吗
Does your son sell drugs out of compassion?
反对
Objection!
请撤回提问
Withdrawn.
你和凯尔文算亲近吗
You and Kelvin are close?
当然
Yes, very.
我手上有你的誓词
I have here your sworn statement
说你对他的贩毒行为还有其他罪行
claiming that you were unaware of his drug dealing
都不知情
and other criminal activities.
要是你们关系亲近 又怎么会不知情呢
If you and your son are so very close, how could you not know?
我总是看到人性的善
I like to see the good in people.
你不行吗
Don't you?
我当然可以
I do.
不过很可惜 本案并无人性之善
Sadly, there is none in this case.
你认识随我出席的助理地检官
Do you know Assistant District Attorney Ward,
-德库西·沃德吗  -认识
- working with me today? - Yes.
那你也认识他的妻子 西沃恩吗
And you know his wife, Siobhan.
对
Yes.
你知不知道她因为被枪击而流产了
You know she was shot, and as a result, she miscarried?
反对 与本案无关
Objection. Relevance.
对 你说明白点 盖
Yeah, help us out, Guy.
你提这些问题是想表达什么呢
Where are you headed with this line of questioning?
卡利尔先生把他的证人
Mr. Kalil has touted the witness
吹嘘成社区模范 诚信标杆
as a champion in her community and a beacon of honesty.
但一旦扯上你家里人
But you're willing to lie, aren't you,
你是很乐意撒谎的 对不对
when your family is involved.
给警方作伪证
Give false statements to the police.
行了
All right, that's enough.
别说了
That's enough.
你可以不回答
You don't have to answer.
你要说枪击受害者
As for people getting shot,
波士顿市的大多数枪击受害者
most gunshot victims in this city are Black
都是来自我们那种社区的黑人
and from neighborhoods like mine.
但没人会为他们伸张正义
But no one's seeking justice for them.
可助理地检官的妻子被枪击了
But now assistant district attorney's wife gets wounded,
就因为他们是住在上流社区的黑人 波士顿人就关心起来了吗
Black couple living downtown, and suddenly Boston cares?
她又比我好在哪了
Is she any better than me?
没其他问题了
No further questions.
我为什么要来这
Why am I here?
我都不知道我来这干嘛
I don't even know what I'm doing here.
可能我是想来看格蕾丝受苦吧
Perhaps I came here to see Grace suffer.
像我 像我们那样受苦
Suffer like I did, like we did.
我早该想明白的
I should've known.
这只会让我自己心痛
Only brought that suffering back on myself.
这些失去与伤痛 惩罚 复仇的循环往复
These cycles of loss and grief, of punishment and revenge.
格蕾丝当然会攻击我了
Of course Grace would attack me.
她自己就在被攻击
She was being attacked!
我不会坐在那任盖·丹利用我们
I couldn't sit there and watch Guy Dan use us
还有我们的伤痛 来伤害另一家人
and what we lost as a tactic to hurt another family.
亲爱的 我在呢
Baby, I got you. I got you.
我在
I got you, baby.
你他妈的脑子出问题了吗
Have you lost your motherfuckin' mind?
能等会谈吗 现在是私人时间
Do you mind? I'm having a private moment.
你没说过会提我的老婆的事
You never said you were gonna bring up my wife!
也许吧 但我也没说我不提
Maybe, but I never said I wouldn't.
我看她像天使一样走进法庭...
When I saw her coming into the courtroom, looking all angelic...
我就想 "这不正好吗"
I figured, "Why the fuck not?"
把我家事掺杂进去 你过分了
You crossed a line bringing my family into this,
你个卑鄙小人
you rat bastard.
卑鄙小人
Rat bastard?
我状态好的时候还真是
On a good day, yeah.
你拿西沃恩受的苦来攻击格蕾丝
You call out Grace for the damage done to Siobhan.
你好好反省下吧 律师大人
Look in the mirror, Counselor.
我投诉了地检官
I filed a complaint against the DA.
盖·丹对你妈妈的提问
What Guy Dan did to your mother
是形式最恶劣的误导证人
was the worst form of witness badgering.
是 那太恶心了
Yeah, that was foul.
我会去压下
I will also try and suppress
科普兰帮枪案的弹道报告
the ballistics from the Copeland shooting.
你很紧张吗
You seem nervous.
没事 是肾上腺素的缘故
No, no. That's adrenaline.
我们是不是会输
We're gonna lose, aren't we?
不好说
Hard to say.
我想上证人席作证
Look, I want to take the stand.
凯尔文 万万不行
Kelvin, no. No way.
极端情况就得用极端手段
Desperate times, desperate measures.
盖·丹会活剥了他的
Guy Dan will slice and dice him.
就刚刚那地检官给格蕾丝搞那一出
After what that DA did to Grace?
让他攻击凯尔文可能是唯一
Attacking Kelvin may be the only thing
能引起陪审团同情的方法了
that gets that jury's sympathy.
坎贝尔先生 你能不能趁我还没古稀
Mr. Campbell, are you gonna answer the question
就赶紧回答问题
while I'm still in my 60s?
去年冬天暴风雪过后 我妈妈
My mother, she got the mayor to send plows
能在卫生部把我们遗忘的情况下
when the Sanitation Department forgot about us
让市长批准调来了除雪机
after last winter's blizzard.
你没有回答我的问题
How is that an answer to my question?
妈妈给我们读了圣经
Mama read the Bible to us.
"己所不欲 勿施于人"
"Do unto others as you would have them do unto you."
可我和我哥哥... 却做了相反的事
But, um... my brother and me... we did the opposite.
时至今日 我罪有应得
I-I deserve to be here today.
我该被收押
I-I deserve to be locked up.
凯尔文 别说了
Kelvin, stop.
我想转为认罪答辩
I'm changing my plea.
法官大人 我请求休庭与我的当事人谈一下
Your Honor, I request a recess to talk with my client.
批准
Granted.
我是有罪的
I'm guilty.
肃静
Order!
为什么 凯尔文
Kelvin, why?
警官 请带被告到后边
Officer, please take the defendant
让他和他的律师单独会面
in the back so that he may meet with his attorney in private.
本庭现在休庭
This court is adjourned.
赢得卑鄙
Dirty win.
有的赢就不错了
I'll take what I can get.
我要去雷吉纳披萨店 要我给你带一块吗
I'm going to Regina's. You want a slice?
手里拿的什么啊
Ooh, what's that?
是录取通知书吗
Your letter of acceptance.
说不定是拒信呢
Or rejection.
你害怕打开看吗
You scared or what?
对啊
Yeah.
其实还不只是害怕
Actually, beyond scared.
怎么了
Of what?
我也说不清 录上了还是没录上 都让我害怕
I don't know. If I don't get in, if I do get in.
拿给我看看
Let me see that thing.
好正式的样子
It's so official, isn't it?
这些玩意都越来越花哨了
These things get fancier and fancier.
我读大学那会儿
You know, when I got into college,
录取通知书就孤零零一张纸
it was a single piece of paper.
"恭喜你被录取了 贷款请背好"
"Congrats. You're accepted. Enjoy debt."
可这一切对我来说都太不真实了
Yeah, none of this even feels real to me.
在我挂了第一门课之前
You know, college didn't feel real to me either.
也可能是第一次宿醉之前
Not until I flunked my first course.
大学生活对我来说都不太真实
Or maybe it was my first blackout.
你那男朋友录上了吗
Your boyfriend get in?
对 他还得了奖学金
Yeah, he got a scholarship.
亲爱的 你经历了那么多
You know, you've faced a lot, Bendrops.
这个你也能面对的
You can face this.
我能面对我的过去 是因为我了解我的过去
I faced my past because I know my past.
可这个...
But this...
-还是你来打开吧  -我可不行
- You got to open it. - No, not me.
太大的压力了
It's too much pressure. No.
我真不行
I can't.
这样啊
Yeah.
怎样啊
Well?
别闹了 爸爸
For God sakes, Dad.
祝贺你 本尼
Congratulations, Benny.
你要在"不夜城"醒过来了
You're gonna wake up in the City That Never Sleeps.
老天保佑
God help me.
我去告诉你妈
I'll go tell your ma.
别 我去给她说
No, I want to.
妈 妈
Mom! Mom!
你在忙吗
You busy?
我在写第七章 "从塞尔玛到蒙哥马利"
Working on chapter seven, "From Selma to Montgomery,"
[由非暴力活动家组织的旨在消除 针对非裔美国人歧视的抗议游行]
但我反正也想休息下
but I need a break.
我听说庭审的事了
I heard about the trial.
都过去了
All over.
你释怀了吗
Are you relieved?
这件事算翻篇了 但另一件还没有
One thing gets solved, another doesn't.
你上次来我办公室是很久之前的事了
It's been quite a while since you've been here at my office.
我想着免得麻烦你多跑一趟
Well, I thought I'd save you a trip to the apartment.
想必你都厌烦来我们家了
You must be sick of our place by now.
况且我也吃腻你做的饭了
And I'm sick of your cooking.
好小的感觉
So tiny.
你还是小孩的时候 看什么东西都觉得大
When you're a little girl, everything seems larger than life.
我觉得我的人生在倒退 妈妈
I feel like I'm going backwards, Mom.
感觉我在工作上 婚姻里 都迷失了方向
Like I've lost my way... in my career, in my marriage.
我们之前谈过这个问题
This is a conversation we've had before.
你工作努力 也在乎你的工作
You work hard. You care about your work.
是什么变了呢
What's different?
我想为我们社区做出贡献 像你那样
I want to make a dent in our community like you do.
像爸爸那样
Like Dad did.
那你可以继续准备竞选市议员
Then recharge your run for City Council.
我还没准备好
I'm not ready for that.
行
Okay.
那你现在打算做什么
What do you have in mind?
要是我说我打算从律所
What if I told you that I'm gonna quit my job
辞职呢
at Rawls & Goodwin?
辞职去做什么呢
And do what?
我想去美国公民自由联盟[提供法律援助的非营利组织工作
I want to work for the ACLU.
这是个... 很激进的转变
That... That's a sharp turn.
我认真的 妈妈 我得弄清楚
For God's sake, Mom, I need to know
做这个决定到底对不对
if I'm making the right choice.
我没法告诉你该怎么做
I can't tell you what to do.
你都在鬼门关前走了一回了
You've been to hell and back.
你比任何人都清楚你自己的想法
You know your own mind better than anyone else.
但我相信
I will say this.
西沃恩·吉斯是我的女儿
Siobhan Quays will do what's best...
是一个厉害的女人
Like the daughter I raised.
她会做出最正确的决定
Like the woman you are.
你看着像快撑不住的阿特拉斯[希腊神话中受罚以双肩掮天的巨人
You look like Atlas about to shrug.
我只是在为这即将开始的倒霉一天
I'm just going through the pregame checklist
做点准备罢了
of the shitty fucking day that lies before me.
不管你碰到什么困难 我都是很乐意安慰你的
I'd be happy to console you over whatever the bumps are,
不过你从来都不说
but you never tell me what's what.
你该谢天谢地
You should be grateful you don't share
我没对你倾诉那些事情 珍
that part of my life, Jen.
爸 妈 我去学校了
Mom, Dad, I'm headed to school.
-回头见  -再见 本尼
- I'll see you later. - Bye, Benny.
我会想念这一切的
I'm gonna miss that.
是啊
Yeah.
卡尔·萨根[天文学家说过
Carl Sagan says that someday
我们有朝一日都能体会到时光倒流
we're all gonna be able to travel back in time.
我倒是不介意再体验下她刚出生的那段日子
I wouldn't mind going back and reliving the day she was born.
那时候生活还很简单
Life was simpler then.
才没那么回事呢
Pfft. Not even close to simple.
我是不会让你打个这么丑的温莎结去见人的
I can't let you loose on the world with a screwed-up Windsor.
过来
Get over here.
来这边
Come here.
真是的
Jeez.
有点讽刺... 这个打法是用一个放弃英格兰王位的人
Kind of ironic that... I wear a knot named after the man
来命名的
that abdicated the throne of England.
不过倒也合适
Well, guess it's fitting.
谢了
Thanks.
罗尔探员 现在由不得你决定
Agent Rohr, you don't get to decide
你是安然无恙还是大势已去了
whether or not this point is covered or laid to rest.
你说得对 柯克兰先生
You're right, Mr. Corchoran.
我的错
My mistake.
只是你万千过错之一吧 罗尔先生
One of many, Mr. Rohr.
是 女士
Yes, ma'am.
你这是在认罪吗
Are you actually contrite?
承认你有过失吗
Are you admitting mistakes were made?
我只承认要想在这么个不安分的地方
I'm admitting that working for 25 years
长达二十五年间都能称得上一个功勋卓著的外勤探员
as a decorated and successful field agent
不是件容易事
in a tumultuous arena has its challenges.
你手下的两个线人...
Two of your informants...
克雷·洛奇和吉米·莱恩 都被谋杀了
Clay Roach and James Ryan... Were murdered.
他们又过的不是什么常人生活
They didn't live casual lives.
你调查过这两起谋杀案吗
Did you investigate those murders?
-没有  -为什么
- I did not. - And why not?
答案很明显
The answer's right in front of you.
我的职责不只局限在死人
My purview is not limited to the deceased.
我负责几十个案子 手下有几十个线人
I carry a dozen cases, a dozen informants.
我没时间去玩找凶手的游戏
I don't have time for whodunnits.
但洛奇和莱恩都有帮助过你破案
Roach and Ryan helped you close investigations,
但你对他们的被害却是什么反应
yet your response to their murders was what?
无所谓吗
A shrug?
我的反应是我该做好我的工作
No, my response was to do my job,
履行我守护宪法
to honor my oath to defend the Constitution
还有波士顿市的誓言
and the city of Boston.
罗尔探员... 你的工作生涯中那一连串被控罪行
Agent Rohr... the litany of alleged crimes committed by you
既令人心烦
in the course of your career is disturbing.
有让人难以置信
It's mind-boggling.
但今天我们之所以约谈你
But the reason you are here today
是因为你与联邦助理检察官
is your involvement in the drug overdose
霍莉·冈纳的过量吸毒一事相关
of Assistant U.S. Attorney Holly Gunner.
她被丢在圣埃里吉斯医院急诊室外
She was left outside the ER of St. Eligius,
而你前搭档赛尔维·克拉斯比
where, not coincidentally,
恰巧是那家医院的安全主管
your former partner, Salvatore Clasby, is head of security.
那我猜你们已经和他谈过了
Who, I'm assuming, you've spoken to.
是
We have.
他怎么说
And what did he say?
他的证词是保密的 但我觉得你心里明白
His testimony is sealed, but I think you know what he said.
罗尔先生 请不要吸烟
Mr. Rohr, please, no smoking.
害不了你的
You'll be fine.
在座各位也不必装什么
Well, obviously, all decorum and impartiality
公平公正了
have gone out the fucking window.
你们让我来这
You dragged me up here to the sixth floor
就是想要搞死我
predisposed to hang me.
我就不浪费你们时间了
Well, let me save you some trouble.
霍莉·冈纳吸太多可卡因吸过量了
Holly Gunner snorted way too much cocaine and OD'd.
我不想她丢了小命 就带她去了
I didn't want her to die, so I took her to the hospital
我朋友赛尔维·克拉斯比工作的医院
where my friend Salvy Clasby worked
因为我以为他能帮下我
because I thought that he could help me
去瞒下霍莉这事
keep her fuck-up a secret!
她还有家庭 有工作
She had a family, and she had a career,
我不希望她因为这一个过失就失去一切
and I didn't want her losing everything over one mistake.
赛尔维 开门
Salvy, open up!
你找赛尔维和特雷西吗
You looking for Salvy and Tracy?
是 我给他们还钱来了
Yeah, dropping off some money I owe 'em.
他们不在家
Yeah, they're gone.
好像是去旅游了
Went on vacation.
他们打算什么时候回来
When are they coming back?
不知道
No idea.
他们倒是带了不少行李走
Lot of suitcases, though.
鸟笼都带走了
They even took the birdcage.
这下好了
Great.
这条线说你会以超优等学位从纽约大学毕业
And this one means you'll graduate summa cum laude from NYU.
你骗我
Liar.
不管怎么说 九月开始的大学生活会很有趣的
Either way, going to college in September should be fun.
有趣吗
Fun?
我们的生活会大变动
Our lives will be entirely different.
我们得强迫自己去上课
We'll have to force ourselves to go to class,
周末打工 自己整理床铺
get weekend jobs, make our beds,
洗衣服 吃食堂的大锅饭...
do our own laundry, eat cafeteria food...
或者说能找到很好吃的披萨
Or find really good pizza.
我们到时候就靠自己了
We'll be on our own.
你说得对 我们完了
Okay, you're right. We're doomed.
对啊
Yeah.
你站起来干嘛
Why are you getting up?
我爸爸告诉我 一位女士进屋的时候 绅士要站起来
My dad says when a woman enters a room, a gentleman stands.
你爸爸还真是个白马王子啊
Wow, your dad sounds like a real Prince Charming.
和我爸就不一样
Unlike my dad.
要喝汽水吗
Do you want a soda or anything?
不用了 女士
No thanks, ma'am.
妈妈 外婆打电话来了
Ma, Non called.
她让我带她去做理疗
She asked me to take her to physical therapy.
你是让她自己打车去的吧
I hope you told her to take a taxi.
本来是这么打算的 但某人把我劝服了
Yeah, I was gonna, but someone convinced me otherwise.
这也是你爸爸告诉你的吗
Is that your father's influence again?
我爸爸说家人总是第一位
My dad always says family first.
外婆还说药房给她配的处方药
Non also was having trouble at the pharmacy
出问题了
with refilling her prescription.
她想问问你能不能
She wanted to know if you could go down there
去帮她处理一下
and straighten things out.
-她自己去不行吗  -她去过了
- Yeah, but why can't she? - She tried.
因为爆粗被药房员工赶出去了
Got kicked out of Hailer's for using foul language.
她活该
Yeah, well, serves her right.
妈妈 外婆需要那些药
Ma, she needs the drugs.
她现在很痛苦
She's carrying a lot of pain right now.
家人第一 妈妈
Family first, Ma.
佛斯特 叫你老爹见鬼去吧
Faust, tell your father he can go fuck himself.
我打算从律所辞职了
I'm not gonna work for Rawls & Goodwin anymore.
出了那么多事 我需要改变
After all that's gone on, I need a change.
现在可能还不是做重大决定的时候
Maybe now's not the time to be making any big decisions.
好吗
Okay?
我被枪击了
I was shot.
安东死了 凯尔文进了监狱
Anton's dead. Kelvin's in prison.
近两个月时间出了太多伤心事了
There's been a lifetime of pain in the last two months,
我知道你和我一样都有所触动
and I know you feel it, same as me.
这一年多时间里
For over a year now,
你都在为了成为合伙人努力
you've been killing yourself to get made partner.
那些都是自负在作祟 我现在明白了
That was all ego. I know that now.
亲爱的 每件事都多多少少和自负相关
Everything is ego, baby.
好坏就看你如何应对
It just depends on what you do with it.
我想去美国公民自由联盟工作
I want to work for the ACLU.
我今早联系他们的人了 明天就面试
I called them this morning. The interview's tomorrow.
你是知道那些案子
You know those cases will put you
又会把你置身在那些社会不公现象的吧
right in the middle of social and civil injustices,
就像我和安东之前的那些瓜葛一样
like, right back to where you started... between Anton and me.
妈
Ma?
我把你的药取来了 但要随餐吃
I got your meds, but you got to take 'em with food,
所以我给你买了三明治
so I got you some sandwiches from Bubba's.
她还在做理疗
She's in physical therapy.
还没到四点呢
That's not till four.
有个更早的位置空出来了
Well, an earlier slot opened up,
她还说服本尼开车载她去了
and she convinced Benny to drive her.
话说你女儿那男朋友
Say, your daughter's boyfriend!
真是个帅小伙啊
He's a handsome little fuck.
她得好好留心下了
She better be careful with that one.
你这话和杰基说的一模一样
God, you sound just like Jackie.
他不喜欢本尼和别人交往
He hates the idea of Benny dating.
我大概也不太感冒吧
I guess I do, too.
不过她是很棒一小孩 在重塑自己的生活
But she's amazing, you know, rebuilding her life.
她不会有事的
She's gonna be okay.
那你呢
Yeah? What about you?
你拿你爸的事问你妈了
You asked Rosa about your father.
是 但她什么都不告诉我
Yeah, and I got nothing out of her.
不稀奇
Big surprise.
你想知道些什么
Well, what do you want to know?
说不定我能告诉你
Maybe I can enlighten you.
这些年我都以为他已经死了
All these years he's dead, and then out of the blue,
结果他还活着 还老找我妈要钱
Ma says he's alive, and he's a mooch.
我都不知道还要知道些什么
I mean, what else do I need to know?
知道更多事情可能不重要
Maybe knowing more isn't important.
要告诉他一些事情才是重要的
Maybe telling him a few things is.
那混账就住这
That's where you'll find the shitbag.
你又一次... 错过我们在落潮酒吧的会面了
You missed our date at the Ebb Tide... again.
我... 我知道
Y-yeah, I know. I know.
我想联系你来着
I-I, I was trying to call you,
但我电话拨不出去了... 就这么回事
but my phone got disconnected, so... so, y-you know.
纽约电信局 你懂的...
The fucking NYNEX, man, you...
一笔话费没交 就...
You miss one payment, right, and...
不管你有没有医药费账单
Just... you may have medical bills, whatever else,
你都会被停机
and they disconnect yous.
双份冰镇龙舌兰
Double chilled Patrón.
-你还记得啊  -算我账上
- You remembered. - On my tab.
我们会起诉苏福林
We're indicting Suferin.
法警这时正准备逮捕他
Marshals are arresting him right now.
那他今天可倒大霉了
Well, that'll fuck up his day.
这个案子证据确凿
You made a solid case.
谢谢
Thank you.
我去你办公室了 他们说你可能在这
Stopped by your office. They said you might be here.
专业责任办公室的人给总检察长的建议是解职
The OPR is recommending termination to the Inspector General.
总检查长一般不会更改意见
He almost always goes along with their recommendation.
我玩完了
I'm out.
正式通知还要等几周再出
Won't be official for a couple weeks.
没有上诉流程 对吧
There's no appeal process, right?
对
No.
想要复职只有另外起诉
You have to go to court to be reinstated.
或者说你可以去特区
Or you can fly down to D.C.
好好跪舔一下联调局局长
and rim-job the Director of the FBI.
弗里[时任联调局局长长得还算不赖
Well, Freeh's a good-looking guy.
闭了眼睛是男是女都一样
If you close your eyes, lips are lips.
巴拉巴的下场都比我好
Fucking Barabbas got a better deal.
[圣经中记载的一名强盗 与耶稣一并被带到犹太人群众前 询问二者中谁该获释 最终巴拉巴被释放 耶稣则被判处死刑]
你反正是高兴了
You're happy.
对不对
Right?
总算把我搞下台了
You got to bury me.
甚至都不用你亲自出手 克拉斯比手里的录像带就足够了
You didn't even need a shovel to do it, just Clasby's tapes.
你被炒是因为那是你应得的
They're firing your ass because you deserve to go.
我重新想了下 还是都算她账上吧
On second thought, she's paying.
"人们从圣经中学会了残忍 掠夺和谋杀"
"From the Bible, man has learned cruelty, rape, and murder.
[出自托马斯·潘恩 美国开国元勋之一]
“因对一个残忍的神的信仰造成了一个残忍的人”
Belief in a cruel God makes for a cruel man."
我想请你保佑我 神父 因为我又犯罪了
I need you to bless me, Father, for I have sinned again.
你们这儿该放个烟灰缸的
You should keep an ashtray in here.
"创世记"第三章第十九条说 我们终究归为尘土 罗尔先生
Genesis 3:19... We all become ashes in the end, Mr. Rohr.
你的朋友梅芙也是
Including your friend Maeve.
愿她的灵魂随主安息
May her soul rest in our Savior's peace.
我想过联系珍妮 看看她人怎么样的
Been meaning to call Jenny, see how she's holding up.
她们俩关系很好
They became quite close.
珍妮觉得她把那笔钱给到梅芙
Jenny is under the impression that she saved Maeve's mick ass
是拯救了她
when she gave her that money.
她没想到那小姑娘头上的枪眼
She has no idea that she actually
也有她的一份力
blew a fucking hole in the wee lass' head,
我也不希望我妻子
and I would like to keep my wife
知道这个残酷的事实
in the proverbial dark about that.
明白了 我向你保证
Understood. You have my word.
你是为这事来见我的吗
Is that what you came to see me about?
是也不是
Yes and no.
我说了我有罪行要坦白的
I said I have something to confess.
是什么罪呢
Yeah, and what would that be?
非法入侵
Breaking and entering.
我不太信得过你 混账神父
You see, I don't trust you, Father Twat.
从来都没信过
I never have.
所以我就去你的私人住所
So I figured that I would check out
稍微检查了一下
your personal space, you know?
找一找有没有儿童色情片 皮鞭 老二戒之类的
See if there's any child pornography, leather whips, cock rings,
能当成你把柄的东西
something I could hold over you.
你的盗窃行径 是想朝上帝 还是朝我寻求原谅
This burglary, are you asking God or me for forgiveness?
我还看了下教区的财务记录
I also looked at the parish financial records.
记得我去年给你的那笔钱吗
Remember that money that I gave you last year?
五千块的捐款
That donation, $5,000?
那笔钱从来没出现在教堂的银行账户上
It never made it into the church's bank accounts.
你在从教区偷钱
You're stealing from the parish.
并且把这笔钱资助给了爱尔兰共和军买军火
And you're giving the money to the IRA to buy fucking guns,
就和那个死掉的可怜梅芙一样
just like poor dead Maeve.
我虽然一直和上帝看不对眼 但我很确定
Now, I don't always see eye to eye with God, but I'm pretty sure
他老人家是不会允许你这样的举措的
that the Almighty would not approve of what you're doing here.
没人清楚主的裁决是怎样的
No one can speculate what God's judgment will be.
我个人而言 是希望你这句话是对的
Well, on a personal level, I hope you're right about that,
但你该担心的是我的裁决
but you should be more concerned about my judgment.
运输军火
You see, trafficking in firearms?
可是联邦重罪
That's a federal crime.
起码五年的刑期
That's five years imprisonment,
你这么个身板会遭不少罪的
which is gonna be hard for a hunk of cheese like you.
我是上帝的子民 但我同样背负使命
I'm a man of God, but I'm also a man with a duty,
保护我的人民不受英国佬侵害的使命
a duty to protect my people against those bloody Unionists,
他们连横穿马路的老妇都会下狠手
who'll murder an old lady simply for crossing the street.
神父 我不是来和你辩论的
Look, I'm not here for a debate, Doyle.
你要是再敢给你那些自由斗士同伙
You send one more fucking dime
哪怕一个子
to your freedom-fighting paddy pals,
我就把你从讲道台上拽下来
and I will drag your ass off of that pulpit
把你拷好了驱逐出境
in handcuffs and straight into deportation.
我回去 就是死路一条
If I go back, I'm a dead man.
那看来我们说好了
So we have a deal.
是说好了 你个恶魔
Yes, you fucking demon.
要是我要你为我作证 你愿意不
And if I needed you to testify on my behalf, would you?
想得美
Not a chance.
嘴硬啊
That's harsh.
那要不给我来个驱魔仪式吧
Well, how about you perform an exorcism?
来嘛 保佑我 神父
Come on, bless me, Father.
Yeah, with pleasure.
-上帝 我...  -不不不
- God, the Father of... - No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
你给我来全套
I want to... I want to see you do-do the whole thing.
整个流程都得来
You know, with the hand and... You know.
来嘛 先出来
Come on, come out here.
我手指 我的手指
My thumb! My thumb!
就当我给你受洗了
Consider that your baptism.
你现在听我的了
I fucking own you now.
孩子... 你怎么了
Baby... what happened?
在这别这么叫我
Don't call me that here.
叫名字就行
Just call me by my name.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
凯尔文
Kelvin.
有话就说 妈妈 没工夫干坐着
Talk, Mama. We haven't got all day.
我... 爱你
I... love you.
这句话也别在这说
Yeah, don't say that neither.
你过得好吗
How are you?
需要点什么吗
Do you need anything?
我想请你别哭了
I need you not to cry.
我不想在我睡觉时还想着你的眼泪
I don't want to think about that when I go to sleep.
好
Okay.
你在法庭上讲的那个故事
That story you told?
冬天里大衣的故事
In court, about the winter coat?
那是很久以前的事了 妈妈
That was a long time ago, Mama.
可你没有变啊
That boy is still in you.
你下周别来了
Look, don't come back next week.
为什么
Why?
不然我满脑子只会盼着你来
Seeing you will be all I think about.
但在这我还得考虑其他事情
And in here, I got to think about other things.
♪ 从汝身上流下的血 会是多么痛苦... ♪
♪ By the blood That flowed from Thee. In Thy Bitter agony... ♪
我今早有事情忘了告诉你了
I forgot to tell you something this morning.
什么事
Yeah? What?
我爱你
I love you.
等等 怎么回事
Yeah, what's... what's going on?
我能问你个问题吗
Can I ask you a question?
正是时候
Perfect time.
为什么选我
Why me?
为什么选我和你结婚
I mean, why'd you choose me?
波士顿学院里那么多女孩...
Out of all the girls at BC, there were lots of...
漂亮聪明有趣的数不胜数
pretty, smart, funny women.
为什么偏偏选了我这个害羞的
Why'd you choose the shy one?
-想让我说好听的吗  -哪有 说实话就行
- Fishing for a compliment? - No, an answer.
我那时候成天趾高气扬的 你知道的吧
I was a pretty cocky son of a bitch, as you know,
我觉得我能调到最好的
and I thought I deserved the best.
但我还是选了你
And I still chose you.
你敢把气氛毁了的话
If you ruin this moment,
我等你睡着了指定给你两刀
I swear to God, I'll stab you in your sleep.
老实回答问题
Just answer the question.
你到底... 看上我什么了
You know, what'd you... What'd you see in me?
我们这些进过海军陆战队的...
Marines, you know...
不用打招呼都能知道对方也是打过仗的弟兄
we can spot each other without even saying "hello."
互相之间都能理解
I can see it in his eyes. He can see it in mine.
我们是经历过同样事情的人
We've been through the same shit.
我从你走路的姿势看出来
Um, I could tell by the way that you walked
你也是经历过磨难的
that you'd been through fucking hell.
虽然和我经历的可能不大一样
Not my hell, your own.
我知道我爸在哪了
I know where my father is.
他还活着 就住在北边
He's alive and lives in the North End.
我真是服了
Fuck me.
他在波士顿吗
He's in Boston?
珍妮弗 别去
Jennifer, don't.
你爸爸就是个人渣败类
Your father is a sleeping dog.
让他自身自灭算了
Just let him lie, fleas and ticks and all.
大伙 快 帮我搭把手
Guys, come on, hand me those bags.
快把旅行袋给我 吉可
Kick, give me the duffel.
快点 还在等什么呢
Come on, what are you waiting for?
该走了
Let's go.
别人可能还愿意待在这破地方
Guys might want to stay in this shithole forever,
我反正是待不下去了
but I'm getting out of here.
那为什么要去佛罗里达呢
But why Florida?
孩子们 快上车了
Kids, come on, get in the car.
背包给我
Give me your backpacks.
快 安全带系好
Go. Seat belt on.
佛罗里达更暖和
It's warmer in Florida.
你们科里婶婶就在那 你们表妹也在那
Corie's there, your cousins are there.
那边的人们也一样喜欢做头发
People got hair down there just like they do here.
我就再开家美发沙龙
I'll start another salon.
你们会进新学校 交新朋友...
You're gonna start a new school and make new friends...
还是更好的学校
Nicer school this time.
你能过上十一岁小孩该过的生活
You're gonna get to be an 11-year-old.
你知道你爸爸过去给我说过一句话不
You want to know something your father always used to say to me?
"不说再见"
"If you don't say goodbye...
"就没那么多思念"
maybe you won't miss people so much."
对波士顿也是这道理
I got to assume the same goes for Boston.
你是谁的女儿
Whose daughter are you?
弗兰基·莱恩的
Frankie Ryan's.
说大声点 听不清
I'm sorry, what? I-I must have wax in my ears or something.
我是弗兰基·莱恩的女儿
I'm Frankie Ryan's daughter.
对了
That's right.
还有谁的
And who else's?
卡思琳·芬尼根·莱恩的女儿
Cathleen Finnegan Ryan's.
这就对了
You're goddamn right.
送你的 波士顿...
Boston...
准备好了吗
You ready?
好了
Yeah.
我真的希望
I really wish they would've let me speak
他们能让我为你辩护的
on your behalf at the hearing.
住房与城市开发部的条例说得很清楚
HUD CCRs are pretty clear.
家里有人犯罪者 全家都会被驱逐
Anybody in your family convicted of a felony, you leave.
规定就是规定
Rules are rules.
照顾好你自己 坎贝尔女士
Take good care of yourself, Ms. Campbell.
他们知道布拉克斯顿顶峰社区收到了两千万的补助吗
Do they know you got the 20 million for the Braxton Summit?
他们知不知道不重要
Them knowing is not important.
能享受到那笔钱带来的改进才是最好的
Better they enjoy the improvements the money'll bring.
下个礼拜日我会在教堂里宣布的
Well, I will tell them next Sunday at church.
像摩西在山顶上那样大声宣布
I will shout that news like Moses from the mountaintop.
是最后的行李了吗 婆婆
Is that the last one, Nana?
是
Yes.
希望来的会比去的好吧
I hope what's coming is better than what is gone.
照顾好你自己
Take care of yourself.
给他来杯双份 一杯酒 花生任他吃
Get this man a double, a beer, and all the peanuts he can eat.
你听说了吧
You heard.
是
Yeah.
我问你个事 老兄
Let me ask you something, D.
要是专业责任办公室叫你作证
If the OPR had asked you to come in
或者我叫你当我的品德证人
or if I'd asked you to, you know,
你愿意不
be a character witness, what would you have said?
算了 还是别回答了
No, never mind. Don't answer that.
谢谢你把苏福林搞定了
Thanks for nailing Suferin.
听说联邦检察办
Heard the U.S. Attorney is prosecuting him
会起诉他侵犯民权
with a civil rights violation.
别谢我
Don't thank me.
谢林登·约翰逊去吧
Thank Lyndon Johnson.
[前美国总统 批准民权法案禁止公民不平等待遇]
我是想自己亲自把那人拿下的
You know, I wanted to take down the son of a bitch myself,
但说实话 联邦罪名
but, truthfully, a federal sentence
比我能找给他的罪名都大多了
is worse than any conviction that I could've delivered.
意思是等我走了你会想我咯
Well... does this mean you're gonna miss me when I'm gone?
你现在打算怎么办
What you gonna do now?
听说圣埃里吉斯医院有职位空出了
I hear there's a... There's a spot at, St. Eligius.
他们在招安保主管
They... they're looking for a, head of security.
我是说 你打算对解职上诉不
No, no, no, I mean, are you gonna fight the termination?
当然了 我找了个律师
Yeah, I got myself a lawyer.
精英人士... 名字老长了
Beacon Hill Brahmin... Fucking guy's got three names.
我要告死那群狗日的专业职责办公室的
I'm gonna take these OPR dicks to court.
就是说可能会找我去作证了
So I may still be asked to testify.
你太太怎么样了
How's your bride?
心乱着呢
In flux.
那听到消息的时候肯定很失落吧
She must've been upset when she heard.
什么消息
Heard what?
凯尔文·坎贝尔...
Kelvin Campbell...
在监狱里斗殴时脑袋挨了一下
took a beating at Walpole, got his skull crushed in.
人死了
He's dead.
我操 真的吗
Holy shit.
怎么了
What?
我没想到... 我也会那么关心
I just... I-I-I didn't think that I would care.
你确实会关心
Um... Well, you do.
这是必然的
Of course you do.
你人就这样
That's who you are.
不 我是个杀手
No, I'm a killer.
我知道凯尔文会死在监狱
I knew Kelvin would die in prison.
还不如让我一枪崩了他
Fuck, I might as well have put a gun to his head and fired.
别想了
Come on.
我们或多或少都是有罪的
We're all guilty of something, kid.
人生都这样
That's the key to life.
这个点谁敲门啊
Jesus, who's this now?
有事吗
What?
乔瑟夫·孔盖米住这吗
Does, Joe... Joseph Congemi live here?
你想怎样
What do you want?
我是珍妮
I'm, I'm Jenny.
他女儿
I'm his, daughter.
他跟你没什么好说的
He's got nothing to say to you.
♪ 阴冷时节 站在窗边 ♪
♪ I was standing By my window It was on a cold and cloudy day ♪
♪ 看着灵车驶来♪
♪ I said when I saw the Hearse come rollin' ♪
♪ 载我母亲离去 ♪
♪ To carry my mother away ♪
♪ 但愿循环不被打破 ♪
♪ Will the circle be unbroken? ♪
♪ 主啊 在不久的将来 ♪
♪ By and by, Lord, by, by and by ♪
♪ 我们终将团聚 ♪
♪ There's a better Home a-waitin' ♪
♪ 在这天上人间 ♪
♪ Lord, in the sky Lord, in the sky ♪
♪ 我紧紧追随着她 试图勇敢支撑住自己 ♪
♪ I would follow Close behind her, Try to hold up And be brave ♪
♪ 但我无法隐藏自己的悲怆 当她被埋在 ♪
♪ But I could not Hold my sorrow Lord, when they laid her ♪
♪ 冰冷墓地中 ♪
♪ Her in the grave ♪
♪ 但愿循环不被打破 ♪
♪ Will the circle Be unbroken? ♪
♪ 主啊 在不久的将来 ♪
♪ By and by Lord, by, by and by ♪
♪ 我们终将团聚 ♪
♪ There's a better Home a-waitin' ♪
♪ 在这天上人间 ♪
♪ In the sky Lord, in the sky Ooh, ooh-ooh ♪
去你妈的
Fuck you.
谁爱要谁要吧
You can have it.
ZIMUXIA.CN
关注新浪微博
@FIX字幕侠
♪ 但愿这循环 ♪
♪ Will the circle ♪
♪ 但愿循环不被打破 ♪
♪ Will it be unbroken? ♪
♪ 在不久的将来 ♪
♪ By and by ♪
♪ 主啊 在不久的将来 ♪
♪ Lord, by, by and by ♪
♪ 我们 ♪
♪ There's a better ♪
♪ 终将团聚 ♪
♪ Better home a-waitin' ♪
♪ 主啊 在这天上人间 ♪
♪ Lord, in the sky ♪
♪ 主啊 ♪
♪ Lord ♪
♪ 但愿这循环 ♪
♪ Will the circle ♪
♪ 不被打破 ♪
♪ Be unbroken? ♪
♪ 主啊 在不久的将来 ♪
♪ By and by, Lord ♪
♪ By, by and by ♪
♪ 我们 ♪
♪ There's a better ♪
♪ 终将团聚 ♪
♪ Better home a-waitin' ♪
♪ 主啊 在这天上人间 ♪
♪ Lord, in the sky ♪
♪ 主啊 ♪
♪ Lord, in ♪
♪ 对啊 ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ 对啊 对啊 ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah-yeah-yeah-yeah ♪
♪ 主啊 ♪
♪ Lord ♪